SECOND-YEAR PH.D. STUDENT · NATIONAL TAIWAN UNIVERSITY

Taipei, Taiwan

About me_

I am a second-year Ph.D. student at National Taiwan University in Taipei, Taiwan. I am a member of the Speech Processing and Machine Learning (SPML) Lab, and I am very lucky to be advised by Prof. Hung-yi Lee. My main research interests broadly cover different aspects of natural language processing (NLP), mainly involving **self-supervised learning** (which has evolved into **large language models** these days), **interpretability** and analysis of NLP Models, **adversarial attacks**, and **human evaluation**.

Education

National Taiwan University (NTU)

Taipei, Taiwan

PH.D. STUDENT IN COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Feb 2022 - Present

- Advisor: Hung-yi Lee
- · Direct pursuit of the Ph.D. degree
- M.S student in Graduate Institute of Communication Engineering (GICE) at National Taiwan University from Sep. 2020 to Jan. 2022

National Taiwan University (NTU)

Taipei. Taiwan

B.S. in Electrical Engineering Sept 2016 - June 2020

Research Experience _____

Supervisor: Dr. Hung-yi Lee

Taipei, Taiwan

NTU Speech Processing and Machine Learning Lab.

August. 2020 - Present

- Large language models and self-supervised learning [3, 5, 8, 7, 6]
- Automatic evaluations and human evaluations in NLP [3, 5, 2, 10]
- Adversarial attacks in NLP [4, 11]

Publications

In Proceedings

[1] Over-Reasoning and Redundant Calculation of Large Language Models

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 18th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 2: Short Papers), 2024, St. Julian's, Malta

[2] Why We Should Report the Details in Subjective Evaluation of TTS More Rigorously

Cheng-Han Chiang, Wei-Ping Huang, Hung-yi Lee

Proc. Interspeech 2023, 2023, Dublin, Ireland

[3] A Closer Look into Automatic Evaluation Using Large Language Models

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2023, 2023, Singapore

[4] Are Synonym Substitution Attacks Really Synonym Substitution Attacks? Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: ACL 2023, 2023, Toronto, Canada

[5] Can Large Language Models Be an Alternative to Human Evaluation?

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 61th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Volume 1: Long Papers), 2023, Toronto, Canada

[6] Recent Advances in Pre-trained Language Models: Why Do They Work and How Do They Work Cheng-Han Chiang, Yung-Sung Chuang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 2nd Conference of the Asia-Pacific Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 12th International Joint Conference on Natural Language Processing: Tutorial Abstracts, 2022, Taipei

[7] On the transferability of pre-trained language models: A study from artificial datasets

Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2022

[8] Pretrained Language Model Embryology: The Birth of ALBERT

Cheng-Han Chiang, Sung-Feng Huang, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 2020 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2020, Online

Workshop Papers

Revealing the Blind Spot of Sentence Encoder Evaluation by HEROS Cheng-Han Chiang, Yung-Sung Chuang, James Glass, Hung-yi Lee

Proceedings of the 8th Workshop on Representation Learning for NLP, 2023, Toronto, Canada

[10] Re-Examining Human Annotations for Interpretable NLP Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

Explainable Agency in Artificial Intelligence Workshop of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2022

Preprints

Understanding, Detecting, and Separating Out-of-Distribution Samples and Adversarial Samples in Text Classification Cheng-Han Chiang, Hung-yi Lee

arXiv preprint arXiv:2204.04458 (2022)2022

Professional Talks

CONFERENCE TUTORIALS

ICASSP 2024 Seoul, Korea

PARAMETER-EFFICIENT AND PROMPT LEARNING FOR SPEECH AND LANGUAGE FOUNDATION MODELS

Tutorial speaker for prompt learning in NLP

ICASSP 2023

PARAMETER-EFFICIENT LEARNING FOR SPEECH AND LANGUAGE PROCESSING: ADAPTERS, PROMPTS, AND REPROGRAMMING

• Tutorial speaker for parameter-efficient learning in NLP

AACL-IJCNLP 2022

RECENT ADVANCES IN PRE-TRAINED LANGUAGE MODELS: WHY DO THEY WORK AND HOW DO THEY WORK

· Main organizer of the tutorial

- Tutorial website: https://d223302.github.io/AACL2022-Pretrain-Language-Model-Tutorial/
- Tutorial recordings: https://youtu.be/thr4-hgLhi8

Honors & Awards

Google PhD Fellowship, Google

Elite Doctoral Scholarship, National Taiwan University 2022 Taipei, Taiwan

2021 Advanced Speech Technologies Scholarship, National Taiwan University Taipei, Taiwan

Professional Activities

REVIEWER 2021-Present

- Conference reviewer: ICML (2023-2024), ACL (2022-2024), EACL (2023-2024), AAAI (2023), NeurIPS (2022-2023), ICLR (2022-2024), EMNLP (2021-2023) and ARR
- Journal reviewer: Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing: 2023

Teaching Assistants

Introduction to Generative AI, 2024 Spring

• The head TA of a course with over 1000 students and 30 teaching assistants

• Oversee the design and grading of each homework

Machine Learning: 2020 Spring, 2021 Spring, 2022 Spring, 2023 Spring

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

Instructor: Prof. Hung-yi Lee

Feb. - Jun. 2024

Feb. - Jun. 2020 - 2023

TEACHING ASSISTANT

TEACHING ASSISTANT

- Gave a 2-hour lecture on diverse topics of large language models.
- Gave a 2-hour lecture on the recent advances in pre-trained language models. Video is available: https://youtu.be/NzElV8jTNmw
- Gave a 3-hour lecture on the adversarial attacks in NLP. Videos are available: https://youtu.be/68lwXWFzCmg and https://youtu.be/68lwXWFzCmg
- Built, designed, and maintained the course website: https://speech.ee.ntu.edu.tw/~hylee/ml/2021-spring.php
- Gave a 2-hour lecture on graph neural network. Video is available: https://youtu.be/M9ht8vsVEw8
- Designed a homework on meta-learning

MAY 14, 2024

2024

TEACHING ASSISTANT Feb. 2020 - Jun. 2020

• In charge of homework on voice conversion

Work Experience _____

National Taiwan University Speech Lab.

System Administrator and Network Administrator

• Managed a Slurm-based system with 20 GPUs

Taipei, Taiwan

Feb. 2021 - Jan. 2022